Sigma Reporting and Performance Benchmarking
Welcome back to our session on quality baseline.
as we come down the backstretch on this topic here.
Let's imagine that we have out in front of us some business.
And in that business, we have a number of key processes that we've identified.
We’ll call that process one
through process N. Where N is some big number. So, from 1 to 2, to 3, to 4, to 5 to N.
Where N might be a thousand or N might be, you know, 500, or whatever.
But that's the critical processes that drives that business.
These are the processes that create this business. That defines this business.
I think we can understand that. Now, each process provides output.
Has some output. I’ll just call output.
And of course every output, in turn, has some number of things
that can go wrong with it. Defect type A, type B,
type C, type D. Same thing here type A. Maybe which is a different kinda A. Type B,
different kind. C and D. Has a host of things that can go wrong with it.
Now, what we can do is take this first process for example.
And let's imagine it's a commercial process.
Let's say for example it’s the hiring process of a corporation
or could be a legal process of some type. Maybe filing for a patent.
It could be a drilling process if it was industrial. Or maybe a wave soldering process.
And it has output with different things that can go wrong.
Well what we do, is we go out and we count, for some number of output.
We count the things that can go wrong.
And from that, we determined the yield of the process.
On the flipside of that is the defects per million opportunities.
Now, once I know the defects per million opportunities of that process.
Let's say for example that it was around 65,000
defects per million opportunities.
That's roughly in this region right here.
So, what I’m going to do, is I’m going to put a little dot right there to represent that process.
Then I go do it again for another process. And this time maybe I find 30,000 defects.
And I do that again for another process.
And maybe I find 50,000 defects per million opportunities.
I make a dot. And I start doing that for all
of my critical processes in that business.
Be they commercial or industrial. And I find them
and they all start coming in right about this region.
So, what I do. Very simply.
These are all my baselines, now. That's a keyword there. That's all my baselines.
That's the baseline of that process. Maybe the patent filing process.
That’s the baseline of the customer documentation process for their needs.
Any number of processes. But the key is this. Look here.
You see them all centered around there? They’re all coming in around
3 or 4 Sigma, with the average at about 3.5 Sigma.
That's how we go about benchmarking.
So, I establish my baseline for all these different processes.
Then I just kinda look at them on a chart like this, where they all cluster.
And I get the baseline of the baseline. Which is around somewhere in here, about 3.5 Sigma.
So, now I can say I got about a 3 1/2 Sigma business.
Now, if I compare that business to say my competitor,
I get some data on them, I’m now benchmarking.
And that's what we will talk about next, the power benchmarking
Thank you for choosing SSMI.